A Guide to the Papers Regarding Hench's Interest in Folklore and Mountain Ballads, 1919-1972
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers Regarding Atcheson L. Hench's Interest in Folklore and Mountain Ballads 1919-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6599-b
This collection consists of ca. 554 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Mrs. Oscar W. Underwood, III, Mr. Hench's daughter, gave these papers to the Manuscripts Department on January 1, 1975.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to Atcheson L. Hench's Ballad and Folklore Collection, 1919-1972, consists of ca. 554 items including his correspondence with other folklore specialists, the ballads he personally recorded, his notes on place names, especially "Folly" and the "Hardware River," publications on place names and folklore, and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
After the correspondence, the material is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- A. L. Hench's Correspondence re Folklore 1919-1969, ca.45 items
- A. L. Hench's collection of newspaper clippings re Folklore 1917-1949, ca.130 items
- A. L. Hench's printed materials re Place Names 1929-1971, 8 items
- A. L. Hench's Collection of Ballads 1930-1937, ca.50 items
- A. L. Hench's Collection of Newspaper Clippings re Place Names 1931-1960, ca. 55 items.
- A. L. Hench's miscellaneous printed material re Folklore 1936-1966, ca. 20 items
- A. L. Hench's miscellaneous notes re Folklore ca. 1939-1969, ca. 90 items
- A. L. Hench's collection of newspaper clippings re Folklore 1950-1972, ca. 60 items
- A. L. Hench's notes on "Folly" and other place names 1963, n. d., 21 items
- A. L. Hench's materials and notes on the Hardware/Hardway/Hardway River 1964, ca. 80 items